Sometimes people think of a large language model as a knowledge store,
有时候人们把大语言模型看作是知识库，
as if it's learned to memorize a lot of information, maybe off the internet,
就好像它学会并记忆了大量的
从互联网上获取的信息，
But I think an even more useful way to think of a large language model is sometimes as a reasoning engine
但我认为更有用的方式是把大语
言模型看作是一个推理引擎，
And then the large language model, LLM,
然后大型语言模型，LLM，
will maybe use this background knowledge that's learned off the internet,
可能会使用它从互联网上
学习的这些背景知识，
but to use the new information you give it to help you answer questions or reason through content or decide even what to do next.
但是也会利用你提供的新信息来帮助你回答问
题，或者推理内容，甚至决定接下来要做什么。
And that's what LangChain's agents framework helps you to do.
这就是LangChain的代理框架能帮助你做的事。
Agents are probably my favorite part of LangChain.
代理可能是我最喜欢的LangChain功能。
I think they're also one of the most powerful parts, but they're also one of the newer parts.
我认为代理也是最强大的功能
之一，但也是较新的功能。
So we're seeing a lot of stuff emerge here that's really new to everyone in the field.
对于这个领域的每个人来说
，涌现了很多新的技术，
how to create and how to use agents,
如何创建和使用代理，
how to equip them with different types of tools like search engines that come built into LangChain.
如何配备不同类型的工具，比如内
置在LangChain中的搜索引擎。
and then also how to create your own tools so that you can let agents interact with any data stores, any APIs, any functions that you might want them to.
然后还有如何创建自己的工具，这
样你就可以让代理与任何数据存
储、API、或者功能进行互动。
So with that, let's dive in.
那么，让我们开始吧。
First, we're going to set the environment variables and import a bunch of stuff that we will use later on.
首先，我们将设置环境变量并导
入一些内容，稍后将会用到。
We're going to use ChatOpenAI.
我们将使用ChatOpenAI。
And importantly, we're going to set the temperature equal to zero.
首先，我们要把temperature参数设为0。
This is important because we're going to be using the language model as the reasoning engine of an agent where it's connecting to other sources of data and computation.
这点很重要，因为我们将使用语言
模型作为代理的推理引擎，它会连
接到其他数据和计算资源，
And so we want this reasoning engine to be as good and as precise as possible.
所以，我们希望这个推理引擎尽
可能地好并且尽可能精确。
And so we're going to set it to zero to get rid of any randomness that might arise.
所以我们把temperature参数设为0
，消除任何可能出现的随机性。
Next, we're going to load some tools.
接下来，我们要加载一些工具。
The LLM math tool is actually a chain itself, which uses a language model in conjunction with a calculator to do math problems.
llm-math工具实际上是一个链，它结合了
语言模型和计算器来解决数学问题。
The Wikipedia tool is an API that connects to Wikipedia,
维基百科工具是一个连接
到维基百科API的程序，
allowing you to run search queries against Wikipedia and get back results.
允许你查询维基百科上的
内容，并返回搜索结果。
Next, we're going to initialize an agent.
最后，我们将初始化一个代理。
We're going to initialize the agent with the tools, the language model, and then an agent type.
我们将用“工具列表”、“语言模型
”和“代理类型”初始化代理。
Here, we're going to use CHAT_ZERO_SHOT_REACT_DESCRIPTION.
这里，我们将使用名为
CHAT_ZERO_SHOT_REACT_DESCRIPTION
的代理类型。
The important things to note here are first chat.
这里面首先要注意的是CHAT。
This is an agent that has been optimized to work with chat models.
这是一个专为与Chat模型一
起工作而优化的代理。
And second react.
其次是REACT。
This is a prompting technique designed to get the best reasoning performance out of language models.
REACT是一种组织Prompt的技术，能
最大化语言模型的推理能力。
We're also going to pass in handle_parsing_errors equals true.
我们还将设置
handle_parsing_errors参数
的值为True。
This is useful when the language model might output something that is not able to be parsed into an action input, which is the desired output.
当语言模型输出的内容无法
被正常解析时，这很有用。
When this happens, we'll actually pass the misformatted text back to the language model and ask it to correct itself.
实际上就是遇到内容无法被正常
解析时，将格式错误的内容传回语
言模型，并要求它自行纠正。
Finally, we're going to pass in verbose equals true.
最后，我们将设置verbose参数的值为True。
This is going to print out a bunch of steps that makes it really clear to us in the Jupyter notebook what's going on.
这会打印出每一个步骤的详细记录，
让我们可以在Jupyter Notebook中
清楚地了解正在发生的事情。
We'll also set debug equals True at the global level later on in the notebook
稍后我们还会在全局级别设置debug为True
First, we're going to ask the agent a math question.
首先，我们要问代理一个数学问题：
This is a pretty simple question, but it will be good to understand what exactly is going on.
这是一个相当简单的问题，但对于我们
了解具体发生了什么非常有帮助。
So we can see here that when it enters the AgentExecutor chain, that it first thinks about what it needs to do.
我们可以看到，当它进入
AgentExecutor链时，首先会考虑需要
做什么。
It then has an action.
然后它有一个ACTION（操作）。
And this action is actually a JSON blob corresponding to two things, an action and an action input.
这个ACTION实际上是一个JSON对象，其
中有两部分内容：一个action（操作）和
一个action_input（操作输入）。
The action corresponds to the tool to use.
action对应的是要使用的工具，
So here it says calculator.
这里写的是计算器。
The action input is the input to that tool.
action_input对应的是该工具的输入，
Next, we can see that there's observation with answer in a separate color.
接下来，我们可以看到Observation（观察结果
）和Answer（答案）是用不同颜色显示的。
Next, we go back to the language model when the text turns to green.
接下来我们回到语言模型，文字变为
绿色，语言模型Thought（思考）：
We have the answer to the question.
“我们得到了问题的答案。
Next, we're going to go through an example using the Wikipedia API.
接下来，我们将展示一个使
用维基百科API的示例。
Here, we're going to ask it a question about Tom Mitchell,
在这里，我们将向它问一个关于Tom Mitchell
的问题（Tom M. Mitchell是美国计算机科学家
，卡内基梅隆大学的教授。他写了什么书？），
We can see once again that it thinks and it correctly realizes that it should use Wikipedia.
我们再次看到它在思考，并正确地
意识到应该使用维基百科工具。
It says action equal to Wikipedia and action input equal to Tom M. Mitchell.
它显示action是“维基百科”，
action_input是“Tom M. Mitchell”。
The observation that comes back in yellow this time,
这次返回的Observation（观察结果）是黄色的，
and we use different colors to denote different tools,
我们用不同的颜色表示不同的工具，
is the Wikipedia summary result for the Tom M. Mitchell page.
这是Tom M. Mitchell页面
的维基百科摘要结果。
The observation that comes back from Wikipedia
从维基百科返回的Observation
is actually two results, two pages,
实际上是两个结果，两个页面，
as there's two different Tom M. Mitchells.
因为有两个不同的Tom M. Mitchell。
We can see the first one covers the computer scientist,
我们可以看到第一个结果
是一位计算机科学家，
and the second one, it looks like it's an Australian footballer.
第二个结果看起来像是一位
澳大利亚足球运动员。
We can see that the information needed to answer this question,
我们可以看到回答这个问题所需的关键信息，
namely the name of the book that he wrote, Machine Learning,
也就是他写的那本书的名字：《机器学习》，
is present in the summary of the first Tom Mitchell.
出现在第一个Tom Mitchell的摘要中。
We can see next that the agent tries to look up more information about this book.
接下来我们可以看到代理试图查
找关于这本书的更多信息。
So it looks up Machine Learning book in Wikipedia.
所以它在维基百科上查找
了《机器学习》这本书。
and it's an interesting example to show how agents aren't perfectly reliable yet.
这是一个有趣的例子，说明代理还不完全可靠。
We can see that after this lookup,
我们可以看到在这次查找之后，
the agent recognizes that it has all the information it needs to answer and responds with the correct answer, machine learning.
代理意识到它已经有了回答所需的所有信
息，并给出了正确答案：《机器学习》。
The next example we're going to go through is a really cool one.
我们接下来要讲的例子非常酷。
If you've seen things like copilot or even ChatGPT with the code interpreter plugin enabled,
如果你见过像GitHub Copilot，或者
ChatGPT的代码解释器插件这样的东西，
one of the things they're doing is they're using the language model to write code and then executing that code.
它们所做的就是用语言模型写
代码，然后执行生成的代码。
We can do the same exact thing here.
我们在这里也可以做同样的事情。
So we're going to create a Python agent and we're going to use the same LLM as before.
所以我们要创建一个Python代
理，使用之前一样的LLM。
And we're going to give it a tool, the PythonREPLTool.
我们会给它一个工具，PythonREPLTool。
A REPL is basically a way to interact with code.
REPL基本上是一种与代码互动的方式，
You can think of it as a Jupyter Notebook.
你可以把它想象成一个Jupyter Notebook，
So the agent can execute code with this REPL.
代理可以用这个REPL执行代码。
It will then run and then we'll get back some results and those results will be passed back into the agent so it can decide what to do next.
然后我们会得到代码运行结果，这些结果会
传回给代理，让它决定接下来要做什么。
The problem that we're going to have this agent solve is we're going to give it a list of names and then ask it to sort them.
我们需要这个代理解决的问题是
让它给一组客户名单排序。
So you can see here we have a list of names, "Harrison Chase", "Lang Chain", "Elle Elem", "Geoff Fusion", "Trance Former", "Jen Ayai".
可以看到我们这里有一组名字，"Harrison
Chase"，"Lang Chain"，"Elle Elem"，"Geoff
Fusion"，"Trance Former"，"Jen Ayai"。
And we're going to ask the agent to first sort these names by last name and then first name and then print the output.
我们要求代理先按姓氏再按名字对这些
名字进行排序，然后打印输出结果。
Importantly, we're asking it to print the output so that it can actually see what the result is.
重要的是，我们要求它打印输出结果，
以便可以看到实际结果是什么。
These printed statements are what's going to be fed back into the language model later on,
这些打印出来的内容将在后
面被反馈到语言模型中，
so it can reason about the output of the code that it just ran.
这样它就可以对代码输出的结果进行推理。
Let's give this a try.
让我们试试看。
it first realizes that it can use the sorted function to list the customers.
它首先意识到可以使用
sorted函数对名单进行排序。
It's using a different agent type under the hood,
它在底层使用了不同类型的代理，
which is why you can see that the action and action input is actually formatted slightly differently.
这就是为什么你可以看到Action和
Action Input实际上格式有些不同。
Here, the action that it takes is to use the Python REPL,
这里，它使用的Action是Python REPL，
and then the action input that you can see is code,
然后你可以看到Action Input是一段代码，
where it first writes out customers equals this list, it then sorts the customers,
它首先写出customers等于这个列
表，然后对customers进行排序，
and then it goes through this list and print it.
然后遍历这个列表并打印它。
You can see the agent thinks about what to do and realizes that it needs to write some code.
你可以看到代理在Thought（思考）该做
什么，并意识到需要写一段代码。
The format that it's using of action and action input is actually slightly different than before.
它使用的Action和Action Input的
格式实际上与以前略有不同。
It's using a different agent type under the hood.
它在底层使用了不同的代理类型。
For the action, it's going to use the Python REPL.
对于Action，它将使用Python REPL。
And for the action input, it's going to have a bunch of code.
对于Action Input，有一段代码。
And so if we look at what this code is doing, it's first creating a variable to list out these customer names.
如果我们看看这段代码在做什么，它首先创建
一个"customers"变量来列出这些客户名称。
And it's then iterating through that new variable and printing out each line, just like we asked it to.
然后遍历这个新变量，按照我们的
要求逐行打印出排序后的名单。
We can see that we get the observation back and this is a list of names.
我们可以看到我们得到了
Observation（观察结果），这是一份名
单列表。
And then the agent realizes that it's done and it returns these names.
然后代理意识到任务完成，返回这份名单。
We can see from the stuff that's printed out,
我们可以从打印出来的内容
看到一些大概的情况，
As this prints out all the levels, all the different chains that are going on,
因为这会打印出所有级别，所
有正在运行的不同的链，
let's go through them and see what exactly is happening.
让我们逐一查看究竟发生了什么。
So first, we start with the agent executor.
首先，我们从AgentExecutor开始。
This is the top level agent runner.
这是第一级的代理运行器。
And we can see that we have here our input,
我们可以看到这里有我们的输入，
sort these customers by last name and then first name and print the output.
按姓氏和名字对这些客户进
行排序，然后打印输出。
From here, we call an LLMChain.
从这里，我们调用一个LLMChain。
The LLMChain, remember, is a combination of prompt and an LLM.
LLMChain，记住，是Prompt和LLM的组合。
At this point, it's only got the input, an agent scratchpad,
目前，它只有input和agent_scratchpad，
we'll get back to that later, and then some stop sequences to tell the language model when to stop doing its generations.
稍后我们会回到这个问题，然后是"stop"
参数，告诉语言模型何时停止生成。
At the next level, we see the exact call to the language model.
在下一级，我们看到了对语言模型的调用。
We can see the fully formatted prompt,
可以看到完整的格式化了的Prompt，
which includes instructions about what tools it has access to as well as how to format its output.
其中包括关于它可以访问哪些工具的
说明，以及返回何种格式的输出。
From there, we can then see the exact output of the language model.
从那里，我们可以看到语言模型的详细输出。
So we can see the text key where it has the thought and the action and the action input all in one string.
我们可以看到text键，其中包含了Thought（思
考）、Action（操作）和Action Input（操作输入）。
It then wraps up the LLMChain as it exits through there.
然后它退出LLMChain。
And the next thing that it calls is a tool.
接下来它调用的是一个工具。
And here we can see the exact input to the tool.
在这里我们可以看到工具的详细输入。
We can also see the name of the tool, Python REPL,
我们还可以看到工具的名称：“Python REPL”，
and then we can see the input, which is this code.
然后我们可以看到输入，也就是这段代码。
We can then see the output of this tool, which is this printed out string.
接着我们可以看到这个工具的输出，
也就是这个打印出来的字符串。
And again, this happens because we specifically ask the Python REPL to print out what is going on.
之所以有这段代码是因为我们特意要求
Python REPL打印出正在进行的操作。
We can then see the next input to the LLMChain, which again, the LLMChain here is the agent.
然后我们可以看到下一个输入到
LLMChain，同样，这里的LLMChain是代理。
So here, if you look at the variables, there's the input.
这里，如果你看"input"变量，
This is unchanged.
这没有改变，
This is the high level objective that we're asking, but now there's some new values for agent scratchpad.
这是我们要代理实现的目标。但现在
"agent_scratchpad"参数有一些新值。
You can see here that this is actually a combination of the previous generation plus the tool output.
你可以看到这实际上是之前的
输出和工具输出的组合。
And so we're passing this back in
我们把这个传回去
so that the language model can understand what happened previously
让语言模型了解之前发生了什么
and use that to reason about what to do next.
并用这些信息来推理出接下来应该做什么。
it is basically finished with its job.
它基本上完成了它的工作。
So we can see here the fully formatted prompt to the language model.
所以我们可以看到语言模型的
完整的格式化了的Prompt。
the response where it realizes that it is done and it says final answer,
它意识到任务完成并输出了最终答案，
which here is the sequence that the agent uses to recognize that it's done with its job.
这是代理用来识别它完成工作的顺序。
We can then see it exiting the LLMChain and then exiting the agent executor.
然后我们可以看到它退出
LLMChain，然后退出
AgentExecutor。
This should hopefully give you a pretty good idea of what's going on under the hood
这应该能让你对代理内部发生
了什么有一个很好的了解，
This debug mode can also be used to highlight what's going wrong as shown above in the Wikipedia example,
这种调试模式也可以用来发现出错的地方，就
像上面的维基百科示例中调用了不必要的查询，
sometimes agents act a little funny and so having all this information is really helpful for understanding what's going on.
有时代理的表现会出人意料，所以这些信息
对于帮助你理解发生了什么非常有帮助。
So far, we've used tools that come to find in LangChain already.
到目前为止，我们已经使用了
LangChain中内置的工具。
But a big power of agents is that you can connect it to your own sources of information, your own APIs, your own data.
但是代理的一大优势是你可以将其连接到你自
己的信息来源，你自己的API，你自己的数据。
So here, we're going to go over how you can create a custom tool so that you can connect it to whatever you want.
那么在这里，我们将介绍如何创建
一个自定义工具，以便您可以将其
连接到您想要的任何地方。
Let's make a tool that's going to tell us what the current date is.
让我们制作一个工具，它会告
诉我们当前的日期是什么。
First, we're going to import this tool decorator.
首先，我们要导入这个工具装饰器。
This can be applied to any function, and it turns it into a tool that LangChain can use.
它可以应用于任何函数，并将其转换
为LangChain可以使用的工具。
Next, we're going to write a function called time, which shakes in any text string.
接下来，我们将编写一个名为time的函
数，它可以接收任何文本字符串。
We're not really going to use that.
我们并不真正使用它。
And it's going to return today's date by calling datetime.
它将返回今天的日期。
In addition to the name of the function, we're also going to write a really detailed docstring.
除了函数的名称外，我们还写了一份非常
详细的DocString格式的注释说明。
That's because this is what the agent will use to know when it should call this tool and how it should call this tool.
因为代理会利用注释中的信息来知
道何时应该调用这个工具（函数），
以及应该如何调用这个工具。
For example, here we say that the input should always be an empty string.
例如，在这里我们说输入应该始终为空字符串。
That's because we don't use it.
那是因为我们不用它。
If we have more stringent requirements on what the input should be,
如果我们对输入有更严格的要求，
for example, if we have a function that should always take in a search query or a SQL statement,
比如，如果我们有一个函数，它应该
总是接收搜索查询或SQL语句，
you'll want to make sure to mention that here.
你需要在这里说明。
We're now going to create another agent.
我们现在要创建另一个代理。
This time we're adding the time tool to the list of existing tools.
这次我们把time工具加到现有工具列表里。
And finally, let's call the agent and ask it what the date today is.
最后，让我们调用代理，问它今天是什么日期。
It recognizes that it needs to use the time tool, which it specifies here.
它意识到需要使用time工具，并在这里指定
It has the action input as an empty string.
它的action_input是一个空字符串。
This is great.
这很棒！
This is what we told it to do.
这就是我们让它做的事情。
And then it returns with an observation.
然后它返回一个Observation（观察结果）。
And then finally, the language model takes that observation and responds to the user.
接着，语言模型根据这个
Observation回复用户：
You should pause the video here and try putting in different inputs.
建议你暂停视频，尝试输入不同
的内容，看看返回的结果。
This is one of the newer and more exciting and more experimental pieces of LangChain.
这是LangChain中比较新，也比较激
动人心部分，还处于实验性阶段。
Hopefully it showed you how you can use a language model as a reasoning engine to take different actions
希望这堂课向你展示了如何将语言模型
作为推理引擎来采取不同的操作，
and connect to other functions and data sources.
并连接到其他函数和数据源。